To this point, in learning the different
ways in which we can use criteria in queries,
we have just used a single criterion. Many
queries require multiple criteria and the key
to using multiple criteria is to use the correct
keywords given a situation. Here is an example.
I have a query with people and locations, and I
am looking for anyone with the last name of Adams
in the city of Los Angeles. I already
have a WHERE clause started to restrict
the query to return people with the last
name of Adams. I will execute the query,
and so far, everything works. When using
multiple criteria, the two main keywords
to use between criterion pieces are AND and OR. We
just have to ask ourselves this: Are we trying to
narrow our results further? If the answer is
yes, then AND is the keyword we want to use.
We do want to narrow this list to show only
those with the last name of Adams in Los Angeles.
To the existing WHERE clause, I will add AND
City = 'Los Angeles'. I will execute this,
and we have just one record
that fits the criteria.